A nice folkloric move is an Arabic traveling to the side with the sharper hip movement.
So that's going to look like this.
Let's put one foot in front, the other one slightly in back and we're going to pull the hip up into our rib cage, really crunching your side muscles and pushing with this leg here using the ball of your foot.
Make sure the leg in the front stays nice and bent.
So it's going to pull up like this.
And we're going to travel with it, so as you do it, as you press up, it's going to allow your other foot in the front to travel forward.
So we're going to go forward, forward as we lock it up.
And up and in, and in.
Other way, in, in, in, in.
Bring it in nice and sharp toward your rib cage. In, in. Good. Make sure you keep your belly button pulled in, and your chest lifted.
Relax your shoulders so you have a nice separate carriage, keeping your body nice and in line with itself.
You can use your arm up here to have a nice, little line going down and priming the hip with the other hands.
Very good.
Now try this in the mirror and make sure everything is moving nicely.